Inventory of the School of Arts and Sciences Records 1926-2008
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
School of Arts and Sciences Records 1926-[ongoing]
Special Collections Research Center
00/02/01/22/UA 310
32.60
School of Arts and Sciences; College of William and Mary. Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains material which may be restricted related to personnel matters, student records, or other reasons. A Special Collections Research Center staff member must review the collection for restricted material before any researchers may use the collection. Consult a staff member for assistance.
Custodial History
This material was previously part of the University Archives Publications Collection.
Historical Note
The arts and sciences comprise humanity's most fundamental and esoteric knowledge, and embrace the creative, reasoning, and analytical processes that are central to shaping our future.Arts & Sciences is the College's largest academic unit, with several dozen departments and interdisciplinary programs. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/School of Arts and Sciences.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains minutes, by-laws, correspondence, and subject files from Arts and Sciences. Included in the collection are Faculty Minutes from 1926 to the present; American Culture Cluster lectures; by-laws; and material from various committees. Also present in the collection is correspondence from the Dean, as well as subject files on degree requirements, the Sharpe Community Partnership Program, and other topics. Acc. 2010.434: Contains correspondence from the Dean of Arts and Sciences to various professors in departments at the College of William Mary from 1964 to 2004. Acc. 2010.435: Contains correspondence from the Dean of Arts and Sciences to various departments in the School of Arts and Sciences at the College of William and Mary from 1988 to 2008. Acc. 2010.632: Contains correspondence between the Dean of Arts and Sciences and various faculty members; minutes from meetings of the faculty of Arts and Sciences; and subject files related to strategic planning from 1994 to 1996. A box list inventory for this accession is available in the digital content line below.
Additional Information
Related Materials
Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences (UA 22); Office of the Dean of Undergraduate Studies (UA 108).
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
College of William and Mary. College of Arts and Sciences; College of William and Mary. Dept. of Fine Arts
Genre/Form of Material:
Bylaws; Correspondence; Minutes; Vertical Files
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--History--20th century.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Publications, 1926-[ongoing]; id72178
  - id59456 (Box 13)
    - Dept. of Russian and Post-Soviet Studies, 2009; id59457 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Sharpe Community Partnership Program, 2001-2008; id59458 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Division of Social Sciences, January 5, 1955; id59459 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - id45578 (Box 7)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1956; id45579 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1968; id45580 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1968-1969; id45581 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1970; id45582 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1970; id45583 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1969-1970; id45584 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1971; id45585 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - id45586 (Box 8)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1971; id45587 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1972; id45588 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1972; id45589 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1973; id45590 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1973; id45591 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Minutes with index, 1973-1974; id45592 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1973-1974; id45593 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - id45594 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Minutes, October 1, 1974-Aril 1, 1975; id45595 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, April 24, 1975-November 4, 1975; id45596 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes (indexed), Oct. 1, 1974-May 13, 1975; id45597 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes (indexed), Oct. 7, 1975-May 4, 1976; id45598 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes, Dec. 2, 1975-May 4, 1976; id45599 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - id59433 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 5, 1976- May 6, 1977; id59434 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 5, 1976- May 6, 1977; id59435 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 4, 1977-April 4, 1978; id59436 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 4, 1977- April 4, 1978; id59437 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 3, 1978- May 1, 1979; id59438 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 2, 1979- Sept. 28, 1981; id59439 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Minutes, Nov. 3, 1981- May 3, 1983; id59440 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 4, 1983- Dec. 3, 1985; id59441 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Faculty Minutes, Feb. 4, 1986- Oct. 8, 1986; id59442 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 9, 1986- Dec. 2, 1986; id59443 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - id59444 (Box 11)
    - Faculty Minutes, Dec. 3, 1986- Dec. 1987; id59445 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, Jan. 1988- May 1988; id59446 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes, Sept. 1988- May 1989; id59447 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 1989- May 1990; id59448 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 1990- May 1991; id59449 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 1991- May 1992; id59450 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - id59451 (Box 12)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 1992- Dec. 1993; id59452 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Minutes, Jan. 1994- May 1995; id59453 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Minutes, Oct. 1995- Dec. 1996; id59454 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Minutes, Feb. 4, 1997- March 2, 1999; id59455 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - id45528 (Box 1)
    - American Culture Cluster, 1995-1996; id45529 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bylaws of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1938-1996; id45530 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Committees, 1970-1995; id45531 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Academic Status, Committee on, 1970-1986; id45532 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - id45533 (Box 2)
    - Admissions Policy Committee, 1943-1983; id45534 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Admissions Policy Committee Minutes, 1970-1983; id45535 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Admissions Policy Committee Reports, Annual, 1967-1980; id45536 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Admissions Policy Committee Reports, Special, 1970-1980; id45537 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Affirmative Action Advisory Committee, 1988-1990; id45538 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Assessment Steering Committee, 1993-1994; id45539 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Assessment Steering Committee Minutes, 1998-2000; id45540 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - id45541 (Box 3)
    - College Assembly, Steering Committee for, 1972; id45542 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - College Calendar, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1974-1991; id45543 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - College Disciplinary Regulations, Special Committee on, 1969; id45544 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Computer Planning, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1979-1988; id45545 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1969-1980; id45546 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1980-1992; id45547 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - id45548 (Box 4)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1993; id45549 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1994-1996; id45550 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Affairs, Committee on, undated; id45551 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Athletic Policy Advisory Committee, 1984-1996; id45552 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - id45553 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Research, Committee on, 1969-1984; id45554 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Studies Committee, 1974-1975; id45555 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gender Equality, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1989; id45556 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Graduate Studies, Commitee on, 1970-2003; id45557 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Honors and Experimental Programs, Committee on, 1969-1996; id45558 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - International Studies Committee, 1983-1996; id45559 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Lectures, Committee on, 1974-2000; id45560 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Library Committee, 1948-1983; id45561 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Library Committee, Minutes, 1971-1975; id45562 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Library Committee Reports, 1946-1996; id45563 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Committee, 1974-1996; id45564 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Registration Advisory Committee, 1974; id45565 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Retention, Promotion, and Tenure, Advisory Committee on, 1974-1996; id45566 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Writing Committee, 1982; id45567 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - id45568 (Box 6)
    - Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1981-1997; id45569 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Dean of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Communications to Faculty, 1968-1979; id45570 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Dean of Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Communications to Faculty, 1980-1995; id45571 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Dean of Faculty of Arts andSciences, Degree Requirements, Academic Regulations, 1970-1972; id45572 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Registration Instructions, 1967-1973; id45573 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Dean of Graduate Studies, 1981-1985; id45574 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Dean of Undergraduate Studies, 1986-1988; id45575 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Development, "William and Mary Alumni in the Arts", 2004; id45576 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Faculty Minutes, 1926; id45577 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Accession 2010.434, 1964-2004; id72179
- Accession 2010.435, 1988-2008; id72180
- Accession 2010.632, 1966-2010; id78616